SAURABH SHARMA





B. Tech Computer Science major with 1 year and 10 months of experience building and deploying AI-driven solutions in agile teams and startup environments across the Agritech, FinTech, and SaaS industries. Skilled in Python, SQL, ML, Neural Networks, Generative AI, and data visualization tools. Translated data into compelling reports and presentations.

Technical Skills

Languages: Pandas, Numpy, NLTK, Sklearn, Keras, Seaborn, Streamlit, Beautiful Soup

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL Metabase

Dashboarding: Looker, Tableau, Power BI, MS Excel (advanced)

Machine Learning: Regression, Classification, Clustering, Deep Learning: ANN, RNN, CNN, LSTM

Generative AI: Models (Llama2, Mistral, OpenAI), RAG, Langchain, Huggingface, LlamaIndex, Ollama, CrewAI

Vector Databases: FAISS, ChromaDB, Pinecone

Other Skills: AWS (SageMaker, Lambda, EC2 Instances), Business Analysis, Business Communication, Active Listening

Experience

Carnot Technologies Aug 2023 – Present

Mumbai, India Data Analyst

• Developed real-time reporting and automated dashboarding pipeline using Looker studio, Metabase, and Python improving reporting efficiency, saving 10 hours per week.

- Implemented ML techniques to predict customers who are more likely to recharge using logistic regression, increasing call picking by 20%.
- Collaborated with **cross-functional teams** to deliver accurate **data-driven insights**, driving improved decision-making.
- Automated Excel dashboards and sheets using Appscript saving 100% of the time required for manual uploading.

Dronapay Jan 2023 - May 2023

Database Administrator - Trainee

Mumbai, India

- Developed efficient scripts for schema creation and master data, resulting in a 50% reduction in schema creation time.
- Ensured schema and data consistency across multiple databases.
- Optimized SQL queries, reducing execution time by 50% leading to faster query and dashboard loading.

Userexperior Aug 2022 - Jan 2023

Data Analyst - Internship

Mumbai, India

- Performed Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) to uncover insights and patterns, Used Random Forest to implement churn analysis successfully.
- Utilized SQL, advanced Excel, and Python for data processing and analysis, and Automated Power BI reports improving report-generating efficiency by 50%.

Projects

- AI Chatbot with memory: Created a conversational chatbot that remembers the context. Using open source models Mistral, Langchain, and Streamlit for webapp.
- Chat with PDF web app: Created an advanced Q/A chatbot, that can chat using personal PDF data. Using advanced Llama3 model, GROQ, FAISS, Ollama embeddings, Langchain and Streamlit for webapp.
- Multi-source model (Agent Usecase): Created a tool to gather data from multiple sources like Wikipedia, arxiv, and websites. Using OpenAI model, Langchain, ChromaDB.

Education

Bikaner Technical University

Aug 2018 – Aug 2022

B. Tech CSE

Rajasthan

Certificates

Full Stack Data Science - AlmaBetter

Sep 2021 - Sep 2022

Contained In-depth knowledge of tools and technologies used in Data Science and Data Analysis.

Python - Great Learning Mar 2021 - Jun 2022

Awards

Gold Badge (Hacker Rank): SQL, PYTHON